[Dreamy music]
[Musik yang indah]
[surprised gasp]
[terkejut terkesiap]
Did you kill it?
Apakah kamu membunuhnya?
No, no, sir.
Tidak, tidak, tuan.
(Beomryong) [Sobbing] Please save me Sir, I really am not.
(Beomryong) [Terisak] Tolong selamatkan aku Tuan, sebenarnya tidak.
I really am not! [siren sound]
Sebenarnya tidak! [suara sirene]
[People are noisy]
[Orang-orang berisik]
(Haejun) With that finger yesterday It would have been impossible
(Haejun) Dengan jari itu kemarin Itu tidak mungkin terjadi
Both of them are wearing red yarn Because he was found tied up.
Keduanya memakai benang merah Karena dia ditemukan terikat.
[Crying] They say you're a communist
[Menangis] Mereka bilang kamu komunis
(Beomryong) I didn’t report it. If you get caught...
(Beomryong) Saya tidak melaporkannya. Jika Anda tertangkap...
(Yoonyoung) Who am I? Where are we now?
(Yoonyoung) Siapa aku? Dimana kita sekarang?
I have passed such a long time you are at best
Aku telah melewati waktu yang begitu lama kamu dalam kondisi terbaik
This is mine
Ini milikku
I did it all
Saya melakukan semuanya
(Yoonyoung) This answer Should I have told you?
(Yoonyoung) Jawaban ini Haruskah aku memberitahumu?
Everything finally becomes clear
Semuanya akhirnya menjadi jelas
to me you are Incomprehensible from beginning to end
bagiku kamu adalah kamu Tidak dapat dipahami dari awal hingga akhir
No, I don't want to understand That I was just a pathetic human being
Tidak, aku tidak ingin mengerti Bahwa aku hanyalah manusia yang menyedihkan
[heavy music]
[musik berat]
(Yoonyoung) What do you mean? That I'm not the culprit
(Yoonyoung) Apa maksudmu? Bahwa aku bukanlah pelakunya
You clearly heard that confession!
Anda jelas mendengar pengakuan itu!
[Haejun sighs]
[Haejun menghela nafas]
I heard it
Saya mendengarnya
Ask a question and get an answer that doesn't fit at all
Ajukan pertanyaan dan dapatkan jawaban yang tidak cocok sama sekali
(Haejun) The question I asked earlier was It was 'why'
(Haejun) Pertanyaan yang saya tanyakan sebelumnya adalah Itu adalah 'mengapa'
[Heeseop’s heavy breathing]
[Nafas berat Heeseop]
(Haejun) What is this?
(Haejun) Apa ini?
Why did you hide this here?
Mengapa kamu menyembunyikannya di sini?
But when asked why The answer I came up with was ‘mine’.
Namun saat ditanya alasannya Jawaban yang saya dapatkan adalah ‘milik saya’.
This is mine
Ini milikku
Don't hesitate to ask for items from your room.
Jangan ragu untuk meminta barang dari kamar Anda.
(Haejun) No matter how embarrassed I was
(Haejun) Tidak peduli betapa malunya aku
Without a single excuse Would you confess like that?
Tanpa satu alasan pun Maukah kamu mengaku seperti itu?
Even if he really did it...
Bahkan jika dia benar-benar melakukannya...
[Sound of door opening] (Okja) Father of five blessings!
[Suara pintu terbuka] (Okja) Ayah dari lima berkah!
(Hyungman) Let go of this! I'm going to kill that bastard!
(Hyungman) Lepaskan ini! Aku akan membunuh bajingan itu!
(Okja) What difference does this make? [Obok’s stopping sound]
(Okja) Apa bedanya? [Suara Obok berhenti]
(Hyungman) Oh, let go of this!
(Hyungman) Oh, lepaskan ini!
(Obok) Ugh!
(Obok) Ugh!
(Haejun) What's going on? [Heavy breathing of the family]
(Haejun) Apa yang terjadi? [Nafas berat keluarga]
(Obok) Uncle Dong-sik takes care of his nephew. He said he put handcuffs on himself.
(Obok) Paman Dong-sik merawat keponakannya. Dia bilang dia memborgol dirinya sendiri.
That bastard, that bastard They say he looks like the criminal who killed my sister.
itu, bajingan itu Mereka bilang dia mirip penjahat yang membunuh adikku.
(Hyungman) Let go of these!
(Hyungman) Lepaskan ini!
Shave that bastard I will tear it apart, I will!
Cukur bajingan itu Aku akan merobeknya, aku akan melakukannya!
(Obok) child, father You can't do that!
(Obok) anak, ayah Anda tidak bisa melakukan itu!
- (Hyungman) I am that bastard... - (Soonae) [Crying] No!
- (Hyungman) Aku bajingan itu... - (Soonae) [Menangis] Tidak!
Hee-seop says that’s not him.
Hee-seop bilang itu bukan dia.
Absolutely not
Tentu saja tidak
[dark music]
[musik gelap]
(Dongsik) This is it
(Dongsik) Ini dia
Is this real?
Apakah ini nyata?
how
bagaimana
How can it not be anyone else?
Bagaimana mungkin bukan orang lain?
Are you...
Apakah kamu...
You!
Kamu!
사람을 죽일 수가 있냐 이놈의 새끼야
Manajemen Risiko 이놈의 새끼야
죽이다니
죽이다니
그게 뭔...
그게 뭔...
이제 와서 오리발 내밀면 뭔 소용이냐!
Bagaimana Cara Menghindarinya? 뭔소용이냐!
all the evidence is wrong Pointing at you, man!
semua bukti salah Menunjuk padamu, kawan!
(Dongsik) That matchbox
(Dongsik) Kotak korek api itu
and a note
dan sebuah catatan
(Yongwoo and Yongsoon) Whoa!
(Yongwoo dan Yongsoon) Wah!
(Yongwoo) Wow, brother, what is all this?
(Yongwoo) Wah, saudara, ada apa ini?
(Hee-seop) Uh-huh Oh, nothing, uh
(Hee-seop) Uh-huh Oh, tidak apa-apa, eh
I need to clean up my room.
Aku perlu membereskan kamarku.
Come out and eat.
Keluar dan makan.
(Heeseop) No. No, it's not
(Heeseop) Tidak. Tidak, tidak
[Crying] It's not me
[Menangis] Itu bukan aku
Nope
Tidak
What is all this? huh?
Apa semua ini? Hah?
(Dongsik) Whose blood is this? huh?
(Dongsik) Darah siapa ini? Hah?
[shaking breathing]
[napas gemetar]
[Grass bug crying]
[Serangga rumput menangis]
Hee-seop last night I came to your house
Hee-seop tadi malam Aku datang ke rumahmu
[Soon-ae sobs]
[Soon-ae terisak]
He saved us yesterday, he
Dia menyelamatkan kita kemarin, he
At Friendship Inn
Di Penginapan Persahabatan
(Okja) Inn?
(Oke) Penginapan?
(Soonae) [Crying] I came because I was worried.
(Segera) [Menangis] Saya datang karena saya khawatir.
He was the one who got hurt
Dialah yang terluka
[Heeseop sighs]
[Heeseop menghela nafas]
(Kyeongae) Um, these cute things, huh?
(Kyeongae) Um, benda-benda lucu ini ya?
What, are you dating, you guys?
Apa kalian sedang berkencan?
(Hee-seop) Yes?
(Hee-seop) Ya?
Oh, what is love? That will never happen...
Oh, apa itu cinta? Itu tidak akan pernah terjadi...
I was afraid I was too surprised to lose, yeah
Aku takut aku terlalu terkejut untuk kalah, ya
I'm worried about Sun-ae, yes.
Saya khawatir tentang Sun-ae, ya.
(Soon-ae) Hurry up, I heard there’s someone to meet.
(Soon-ae) Cepatlah, kudengar ada seseorang yang perlu ditemui.
Um, go, go
Ayo, ayo
You cat-like bastard.
Dasar bajingan seperti kucing.
(Kyeongae) Ah, Chi.
(Kyeongae) Ah, Chi.
Hey
Hei
be nice to my little brother
bersikap baiklah pada adikku
Yo, yo, yo with that cute face, huh? Don't go around fighting
Yo, yo, yo dengan wajah imut itu ya? Jangan seenaknya berkelahi
- Got it? - (Heeseop) Yes, I understand.
- Mengerti? - (Heeseop) Ya, saya mengerti.
It was good
Itu bagus
(Soonae) [Small] Go, please
(Soonae) [Kecil] Silakan pergi
- Come in early - (Kyungae) Yes
- Datanglah lebih awal - (Kyungae) Ya
I'm really getting scolded by my mom and dad.
Aku benar-benar dimarahi oleh ibu dan ayahku.
Are you coming?
Apakah kamu datang?
(Kyungae) This girl will disappear
(Kyungae) Gadis ini akan menghilang
[smirk] Ah have a good time
[menyeringai] Ah selamat bersenang-senang
Here we go!
Ini dia!
- (Soonae) Come in early! - (Kyeong-Ae) Yes, lady!
- (Soonae) Datanglah lebih awal! - (Kyeong-Ae) Ya, nona!
Oh, Lee Kyung-ae really
Oh, Lee Kyung-ae sungguh
Why is it like that?
Mengapa seperti itu?
- Injured Den - (Hee-seop) Oh, yeah
- Sarang yang Terluka - (Hee-seop) Oh, ya
Are you okay?
Apakah kamu baik-baik saja?
It's okay, yeah
Tidak apa-apa, ya
(Heeseop) What am I doing? You can just apply soybean paste or soybean paste.
(Heeseop) Apa yang aku lakukan? Anda cukup mengoleskan pasta kedelai atau pasta kedelai.
Well, I saw something decent. Then I'll just...
Yah, aku melihat sesuatu yang bagus. Kalau begitu aku hanya akan...
There are a lot of them on the roof of my house?
Ada banyak dari mereka di atap rumah saya?
soybean paste
pasta kedelai
(Okja) Rooftop?
(Oke) Atap?
[heavy music] Rooftop? The rooftop of my house?
[musik berat] Atap? Atap rumahku?
You two were together that night?
Kalian berdua bersama malam itu?
[Okja sighs]
[Okja menghela nafas]
(Haejun) What time exactly?
(Haejun) Jam berapa tepatnya?
Do you even remember how long we were together?
Apakah kamu ingat berapa lama kita bersama?
That's it
Itu saja
Until my sister comes Just because I said I would wait with you
Sampai adikku datang Hanya karena aku bilang aku akan menunggu bersamamu
(Pure love) Until the sun rises We were together all night
(Cinta murni) Sampai matahari terbit Kami bersama sepanjang malam
So, Hee-seop is absolutely Could be the culprit...
Jadi, Hee-seop tentu saja Bisa jadi pelakunya...
(Hyungman) That story
(Hyungman) Cerita itu
Does anyone know anything else?
Apakah ada yang tahu hal lain?
no
tidak
There won't be any
Tidak akan ada apapun
(Hyungman) From now on
(Hyungman) Mulai sekarang
Then what about Hee-seop?
Lalu bagaimana dengan Hee-seop?
(Hyungman) That damn ‘Hee-seop, Hee-seop’!
(Hyungman) 'Hee-seop, Hee-seop' sialan itu!
Since when did you know the guy’s name? They call me so friendly!
Sejak kapan kamu tahu nama pria itu? Mereka memanggilku dengan sangat ramah!
People say your sister Is it because you don't know what you're whispering about?
Orang bilang adikmu Apakah karena kamu tidak tahu apa yang kamu bisikkan?
To that distant abandoned house that night Why would you go?
Ke rumah yang ditinggalkan jauh malam itu Mengapa kamu pergi?
After drinking, I went to meet some guys.
Setelah minum, saya pergi menemui beberapa pria.
They talk so carelessly Don't you know!
Mereka berbicara sembarangan Tahukah kamu!
[Sobbing]
[Menangis]
My second daughter is with some guy. on the roof of their house
Putri keduaku bersama seorang pria. di atap rumah mereka
I guess they dated all night long
Saya kira mereka berkencan sepanjang malam
At the bottom of this narrow countryside There are all kinds of dirty rumors going around.
Di bagian bawah pedesaan sempit ini Ada berbagai macam rumor kotor yang beredar.
It's an instant!
Ini sekejap!
you
kamu
to your mom Should I even tell you that story?
kepada ibumu Haruskah aku menceritakan kisah itu padamu?
father!
ayah!
(Hyungman) If there is no sin It'll work out on its own
(Hyungman) Jika tidak ada dosa Itu akan berjalan dengan sendirinya
So
Jadi
no one, never
tidak seorang pun, tidak pernah
Don't say that out loud
Jangan katakan itu keras-keras
[sigh]
[menghela nafas]
teacher
guru
It's shameless
Itu tidak tahu malu
Just some
Hanya beberapa
Please
Tolong
[Tapping sound] [Typewriter operating sound]
[Mengetuk suara] [Suara pengoperasian mesin tik]
(Class President) Ah, this bastard. Keep your mouth shut
(Ketua Kelas) Ah, bajingan ini. Tutup mulutmu
This is a complete bastard!
Ini benar-benar bajingan!
야, 이거 피해자 죽일 때 튄 거 맞잖아
야, 이거 피해자 죽일 때 튄 거 맞잖아
어젯밤에 이경애 머리 깨트릴 때 폐가에서, 이 새끼야
Bagaimana Cara Mengatasinya? 폐가에서, 이 새끼야
대답해, 이 새끼야!
Ya, sungguh!
I will do it
Saya akan melakukannya
(Class President) [Sighing] Ugh
(Ketua Kelas) [Menghela napas] Ugh
How can you do that, family?
Bagaimana kamu bisa melakukan itu, keluarga?
I'll cry
aku akan menangis
That's not even legal
Itu bahkan tidak sah
Hey, get this bastard to open his mouth.
Hei, suruh bajingan ini membuka mulutnya.
(Detective 1) Ah, yes, Captain. [dark music]
(Detektif 1) Ah, ya, Kapten. [musik gelap]
let's go
ayo pergi
(Detective 2) Come to work
(Detektif 2) Ayo kerja
[Moon So-ri]
[Bulan So-ri]
(Haejun) During the conversation earlier, You said you had someone to meet, right?
(Haejun) Selama percakapan tadi, Kamu bilang kamu punya seseorang untuk ditemui, kan?
When Kyoung-ae left that night
Saat Kyoung-ae pergi malam itu
Ah, yes
Ya, ya
But he was a very nice person.
Tapi dia adalah orang yang sangat baik.
(Soonae) Sister He is the benefactor who saved me during the day.
(Segera) Kakak Dia adalah dermawan yang menyelamatkan saya sepanjang hari.
[intense music]
[musik yang intens]
(Yoonyoung) Who is it already? You guessed it, right?
(Yoonyoung) Sudah siapa? Anda dapat menebaknya, bukan?
(Haejun) If the confession was wrong
(Haejun) Jika pengakuannya salah
The reason Baek Hee-seop deserves it is Because there is only one
Alasan Baek Hee-seop pantas mendapatkannya adalah Karena hanya ada satu
(Yoonyoung) As expected, my father What I wanted to protect
(Yoonyoung) Seperti yang diharapkan, ayahku Apa yang ingin saya lindungi
It wasn't my mom
Itu bukan ibuku
[Rough fighting sounds]
[Suara pertarungan yang kasar]
(Yuseop) Are you hurt?
(Yuseop) Apakah kamu terluka?
(Yoonyoung) That night, Lee Kyung-ae The last person I went to see
(Yoonyoung) Malam itu, Lee Kyung-ae Orang terakhir yang kutemui
Blue hat, Baek Yu-seop
Topi biru, Baek Yu-seop
I felt terrible my whole life That damn brother again
Saya merasa tidak enak sepanjang hidup saya Kakak sialan itu lagi
I was trying to cover it up, my father
Aku mencoba untuk menutupinya, ayahku
It was Hee-seop earlier. Is it Yusup this time?
Itu adalah Hee-seop sebelumnya. Apakah kali ini Yusup?
(Dongsik’s wife) Last time For saving our dragon
(Istri Dongsik) Terakhir kali Untuk menyelamatkan naga kita
Thank you so much I think so, teacher.
Terima kasih banyak Saya kira begitu, guru.
What the hell is at my house Why are you doing that?
Ada apa di rumahku Mengapa kamu melakukan itu?
(Yoonyoung) Doing more difficult work There is also a house that is going through hardships.
(Yoonyoung) Melakukan pekerjaan yang lebih sulit Ada juga rumah yang sedang mengalami kesulitan.
Don't you know, in this town now?
Tahukah kamu, di kota ini sekarang?
(Dongsik’s wife) Solving that problem It's up to our kids' father.
(Istri Dongsik) Menyelesaikan masalah itu Terserah ayah anak-anak kita.
Personally, I really want to ask you That's because
Secara pribadi, saya sangat ingin bertanya kepada Anda Itu karena
(Haejun) Anyway You should have contacted me.
(Haejun) Pokoknya Anda seharusnya menghubungi saya.
To deliver news about Baek Hee-seop
Untuk menyampaikan berita tentang Baek Hee-seop
It has to be
Itu harus
Haven't you even come to the boarding house? They say it’s already been 3 days
Kamu malah belum datang ke kosnya? Mereka bilang ini sudah 3 hari
It happens often.
Hal ini sering terjadi.
(Dongsik’s office) in Seoul Even though I went to that good university
(Kantor Dongsik) di Seoul Meskipun saya kuliah di universitas bagus itu
I said I would come pick up my brother later. It's an anime that goes to the factory every now and then.
Aku bilang aku akan menjemput adikku nanti. Ini adalah anime yang sesekali masuk ke pabrik.
[Meaningful music] (Yoonyoung) Uncle?
[Musik yang bermakna] (Yoonyoung) Paman?
(Dongsik’s wife) My younger brother How terrible I think
(Istri Dongsik) Adik laki-laki saya Betapa buruknya menurutku
In the meantime [sigh]
Sementara itu [menghela nafas]
Come down every weekend
Datanglah setiap akhir pekan
among themselves I said I was going to see your face.
di antara mereka sendiri Aku bilang aku akan melihat wajahmu.
Well, I stayed at the boarding house properly. Do you even have time to sleep?
Yah, aku menginap di kos dengan baik. Apakah kamu bahkan punya waktu untuk tidur?
Oh my, oh my, it hurts, really
Ya ampun, ya ampun, sakit sekali
(Haejun) The location of the boarding house is What happens?
(Haejun) Lokasi kosnya Apa yang terjadi?
I said it was near the school
Aku bilang itu dekat sekolah
I said somewhere in Sillim-dong.
Kataku di suatu tempat di Sillim-dong.
Sillim-dong?
Sillim-dong?
(Yoonyoung) He was a student at Seoul National University. Uncle?
(Yoonyoung) Dia adalah seorang mahasiswa di Universitas Nasional Seoul. Paman?
Seoul National University, Department of Korean Literature, 3rd year
Universitas Nasional Seoul, Jurusan Sastra Korea, tahun ke-3
(Byunggu) From now on, with you all We will be together for a month
(Byunggu) Mulai sekarang, bersama kalian semua Kami akan bersama selama sebulan
This is student Lee Joo-young.
Ini adalah siswa Lee Joo-young.
Seoul National University Department of Korean Literature I'm a 4th grade student
Departemen Sastra Korea Universitas Nasional Seoul Saya seorang siswa kelas 4
Same school, same department
Sekolah yang sama, jurusan yang sama
[sigh]
[menghela nafas]
Even with the first victim I mean there was a point of contact.
Bahkan dengan korban pertama Maksudku, ada titik kontaknya.
(Yoonyoung) Everyone Because you hid it like that
(Yoonyoung) Semuanya Karena kamu menyembunyikannya seperti itu
How could you have doubted
Bagaimana mungkin kamu ragu
My father said he would protect his brother. Instead, they even got caught.
Ayahku berkata dia akan melindungi saudaranya. Sebaliknya, mereka malah tertangkap.
My maternal grandfather I pretend not to know because the rumors in the neighborhood are scary
Kakek dari pihak ibu saya Saya pura-pura tidak tahu karena rumor di lingkungan sekitar sangat menakutkan
Thanks to Baek Yoo-seop I was able to hide away.
Terima kasih kepada Baek Yoo-seop Saya bisa bersembunyi.
But it's still like that
Tapi tetap saja seperti itu
How is it not even mentioned?
Bagaimana bisa tidak disebutkan?
It happened once, very briefly.
Itu terjadi sekali, sangat singkat.
As if passing by once
Seolah lewat sekali
(Detective 2) Listen straight, you bastard! [crash sound]
(Detektif 2) Dengarkan baik-baik, bajingan! [suara tabrakan]
[clacking sound] (Detective 1) Hey, come to your senses.
[suara klak] (Detektif 1) Hei, sadarlah.
Look here, huh?
Lihat di sini, ya?
Look at me! [sigh]
Lihat aku! [menghela nafas]
[The sound continues]
[Suara berlanjut]
Ic, that's gross, really, ah
Ic, itu menjijikkan, sungguh, ah
(Detective 2) Talk to me, really!
(Detektif 2) Bicaralah padaku, sungguh!
(Detective 3) Captain
(Detektif 3) Kapten
Police officer Kim near an abandoned house I heard you picked something like this up
Petugas polisi Kim di dekat rumah yang ditinggalkan Saya mendengar Anda mengambil sesuatu seperti ini
- (Class leader) Near an abandoned house? - (Detective 3) Yes
- (Ketua kelas) Dekat rumah kosong? - (Detektif 3) Ya
Should I upload this as evidence?
Haruskah saya mengunggah ini sebagai bukti?
(Class President) What is this again?
(Ketua Kelas) Apa ini lagi?
(Detective 3) Write, ya This looks like a necklace, right?
(Detektif 3) Tulislah, ya Ini terlihat seperti kalung, kan?
(Class President) Hey, try it.
(Ketua Kelas) Hei, cobalah.
(Detective 3) What is this? Just put it around your neck...
(Detektif 3) Apa ini? Letakkan saja di lehermu...
[Dongsik’s urgent breathing] [nervous music]
[Nafas Dongsik yang mendesak] [musik gugup]
(Class President) Hey!
(Ketua Kelas) Hei!
(Detective 2) Ah, earlier He said he confessed...
(Detektif 2) Ah, tadi Dia bilang dia mengaku...
[Heeseop chuckles]
[Heeseop terkekeh]
(Dongsik) Hee-seop, Hee-seop
(Dongsik) Hee-seop, Hee-seop
Are you okay? uh? Hee-seop
Apakah kamu baik-baik saja? eh? Hee-seop
[Sound of clicking open] (Detective 1) What is it?
[Suara klik terbuka] (Detektif 1) Ada apa?
(Class President) Hey, Baek Dong-sik!
(Ketua Kelas) Hei, Baek Dong-sik!
What are you doing, this!
Apa yang kamu lakukan, ini!
(Dongsik) Hee-seop Hee-seop, come to your senses, okay?
(Dongsik) Hee-seop Hee-seop, sadarlah, oke?
This, this
Ini, ini
Your brother, huh?
Adikmu, ya?
It’s Yusuf, right? huh?
Itu Yusuf, kan? Hah?
Get it straight, man!
Luruskan, kawan!
This is mine
Ini milikku
(Detective 2) Hey This idiot, this, this
(Detektif 2) Hei Si bodoh ini, ini, ini
The mouth that won't open even if you get hit It's finally opened, this
Mulut yang tidak mau terbuka meskipun terkena pukulan Akhirnya dibuka, ini
[Detective 2 laughs]
[Detektif 2 tertawa]
I lent it to you for a short time. It's been a while since I got it back
Saya meminjamkannya kepada Anda untuk waktu yang singkat. Sudah lama sejak saya mendapatkannya kembali
(Heeseop) This It was all mine from the start
(Heeseop) Ini Itu semua milikku sejak awal
(Yoonyoung) No, it’s my father’s
(Yoonyoung) Bukan, itu milik ayahku
I'm sure
saya yakin
From childhood
Sejak kecil
My uncle said it was his Because I couldn't even touch it
Pamanku bilang itu miliknya Karena aku bahkan tidak bisa menyentuhnya
Baek Hee-seop will insist that it’s his.
Baek Hee-seop akan bersikeras bahwa itu miliknya.
(Haejun) It will work in reality
(Haejun) Ini akan berhasil dalam kenyataan
If it's the way it is, no matter what you do anyway Although I am set to be released
Jika memang begitu, apa pun yang Anda lakukan Meskipun saya siap untuk dibebaskan
This time because of a confession I don't know how things will turn out
Kali ini karena sebuah pengakuan Saya tidak tahu bagaimana jadinya nanti
We need to find Baek Yu-seop as quickly as possible.
Kita harus menemukan Baek Yu-seop secepat mungkin.
Is it really all you have to do is find it?
Benarkah yang perlu Anda lakukan hanyalah menemukannya?
Anyway, that necklace
Bagaimanapun, kalung itu
Proving the circumstances of the murder I told you it would be difficult
Membuktikan keadaan pembunuhan itu Sudah kubilang itu akan sulit
Because the time and place of separation are ambiguous
Sebab waktu dan tempat perpisahannya tidak jelas
So in advance I'll find one
Jadi sebelumnya Aku akan menemukannya
[Meaningful music]
[Musik yang bermakna]
lost evidence
bukti yang hilang
[sigh]
[menghela nafas]
(Haejun) That shirt from earlier
(Haejun) Baju yang tadi
That's much more important evidence than you think It could have been
Itu adalah bukti yang jauh lebih penting daripada yang Anda kira Itu bisa saja terjadi
- (Detective 3) Police Officer Kim - (Officer Kim) Oh my, Detective Lee.
- (Detektif 3) Petugas Polisi Kim - (Petugas Kim) Ya ampun, Detektif Lee.
- (Detective 3) Hey - (Police officer Kim) Loyalty
- (Detektif 3) Hei - (Petugas polisi Kim) Kesetiaan
- (Detective 3) Is Jesu okay? - (Police officer Kim) Oh, of course.
- (Detektif 3) Apakah Jesu baik-baik saja? - (Petugas polisi Kim) Oh, tentu saja.
(Haejun) There is still no such thing as scientific investigation In a very unfamiliar era
(Haejun) Masih belum ada yang namanya penyelidikan ilmiah Di era yang sangat asing
One small mistake
Satu kesalahan kecil
[Sound of car door closing] [Car starting sound]
[Suara pintu mobil ditutup] [Suara start mobil]
[tire rubbing sound]
[suara gesekan ban]
(Haejun) Everything in an instant Even if I didn't ruin it
(Haejun) Semuanya dalam sekejap Meski aku tidak merusaknya
Mistress
Nyonya
(Haejun) Contaminated evidence [Police officer Kim sighs]
(Haejun) Bukti yang terkontaminasi [Petugas polisi Kim menghela nafas]
So no results What I didn't get wasn't enough
Jadi tidak ada hasil Apa yang tidak saya dapatkan tidaklah cukup
After the investigation is concluded I even lost it forever.
Setelah penyelidikan selesai Aku bahkan kehilangannya selamanya.
To the possibilities of the distant future It was completely destroyed.
Untuk kemungkinan-kemungkinan di masa depan yang jauh Itu hancur total.
It will be different this time
Kali ini akan berbeda
If only the evidence survives, Baek Yu-seop
Andai saja buktinya masih ada, Baek Yu-seop
Now nowhere You won't be able to hide.
Sekarang tidak ada tempat Anda tidak akan bisa bersembunyi.
[Police officer Kim is humming]
[Petugas polisi Kim bersenandung]
(Haejun) Oh, I It's dangerous to drive with something like this.
(Haejun) Hei, aku Berbahaya mengemudi dengan hal seperti ini.
(Police officer Kim) Oh, what is it?
(Petugas polisi Kim) Oh, ada apa?
(Haejun) Is that it?
(Haejun) Apakah itu?
Detective Lee forgot.
Detektif Lee lupa.
Because it's important Please put it in well and take it with you.
Karena itu penting Silakan masukkan dengan baik dan bawa bersama Anda.
yes
ya
[Interesting music]
[Musik yang menarik]
(Haejun) Go safely and carefully.
(Haejun) Pergilah dengan aman dan hati-hati.
yes
ya
[Car starting sound]
[Suara start mobil]
(Haejun) Until the results come out I'll come find Baek Yu-seop
(Haejun) Sampai hasilnya keluar Aku akan datang mencari Baek Yu-seop
Schools, factories, boarding houses I'll search every possible place.
Sekolah, pabrik, kos-kosan Saya akan mencari di setiap tempat yang memungkinkan.
Sillim-dong, Seoul
Sillim-dong, Seoul
(Soonae) [Sobbing] Father
(Soonae) [Menangis] Ayah
[sound of banging] Father!
[suara gedoran] Ayah!
Father, please open it!
Ayah, tolong buka!
This isn't it
Ini bukan itu
What other people say What's important?
Apa yang orang lain katakan Apa yang penting?
[Sad music]
[Musik sedih]
Hee-seop is
Hee-seop adalah
Talk about yourself with your own mouth I'm saying I'll never bring it up.
Bicarakan tentang dirimu dengan mulutmu sendiri Maksudku, aku tidak akan pernah mengungkitnya.
father
ayah
I hate myself so much too
Aku juga sangat membenci diriku sendiri
I never thought my sister would become like this Without knowing it completely
Aku tidak menyangka adikku akan menjadi seperti ini Tanpa menyadarinya sepenuhnya
If I had stopped you from going then
Kalau saja aku menghentikanmu untuk pergi, maka
Sister, it wouldn't have happened like that.
Saudari, hal seperti itu tidak akan terjadi.
I should have caught you then
Seharusnya aku menangkapmu saat itu
I feel like it's all my fault
Aku merasa ini semua salahku
I'm really so terrible
Aku sungguh sangat buruk
I hate you so much
Aku sangat membencimu
Dad, still
Ayah, masih
we are sisters
kita adalah saudara perempuan
Even if I lost my sister
Walaupun aku kehilangan adikku
No matter what happens to other people Leave it as is
Tidak peduli apa yang terjadi pada orang lain Biarkan apa adanya
That's not it
Bukan itu
Then it really doesn't work.
Maka itu benar-benar tidak berhasil.
[shaking breathing]
[napas gemetar]
[Heavy breathing]
[Nafas berat]
[Sound of window opening]
[Suara jendela terbuka]
(Soonae) Yoonyoung, help me
(Soonae) Yoonyoung, bantu aku
[heavy music]
[musik berat]
Where are you going now?
Kemana kamu pergi sekarang?
police station
kantor polisi
(Soonae) Are you still there? If you're being caught, you need to make it clear.
(Segera) Apakah kamu masih di sana? Jika Anda tertangkap, Anda harus menjelaskannya.
How scared is Hee-seop alone right now?
Seberapa takutkah Hee-seop sendirian saat ini?
I have to go quickly
Saya harus pergi dengan cepat
(Yoonyoung) Stop it
(Yoonyoung) Hentikan
Now is not the time for you to step out
Sekarang bukan waktunya bagi Anda untuk keluar
What does it mean?
Apa maksudnya?
Adults will take care of everything
Orang dewasa akan mengurus semuanya
(Yoonyoung) So If you just wait...
(Yoonyoung) Jadi Jika kamu hanya menunggu...
What adults?
Orang dewasa apa?
(Soonae) Even though I don’t really know
(Soonae) Meskipun aku tidak begitu tahu
Recklessly, my nephew Put them in handcuffs and drag them away
Ceroboh, keponakanku Borgol mereka dan seret mereka pergi
Made the rumor spread around the neighborhood An adult like that?
Membuat rumor tersebut menyebar ke seluruh lingkungan sekitar Orang dewasa seperti itu?
For you, Mr. Yoon To me, mom and dad
Untukmu, Tuan Yoon Bagiku, ibu dan ayah
I will protect you and protect you unconditionally. If there were adults, I wouldn't be like this either.
Aku akan melindungimu dan melindungimu tanpa syarat. Jika ada orang dewasa, saya juga tidak akan seperti ini.
[Crying] But for Hee-seop There's no one
[Menangis] Tapi untuk Hee-seop Tidak ada seorang pun
I have to go
Saya harus pergi
(Yoonyoung) If you don’t know, just stay still.
(Yoonyoung) Jika kamu tidak tahu, diam saja.
Are all police idiots?
Apakah semua polisi idiot?
Baek Hee-seop became like that It's all your fault!
Baek Hee-seop menjadi seperti itu Ini semua salahmu!
(Soonae) What do you know!
(Segera) Apa yang kamu tahu!
I have to go
Saya harus pergi
Let go!
Lepaskan!
Let go, please
Tolong lepaskan
I have to go
Saya harus pergi
[Sobbing]
[Menangis]
I promised
saya berjanji
I promised...
aku berjanji...
[Grass bug crying]
[Serangga rumput menangis]
[Heeseop laughs]
[Heeseop tertawa]
(Hee-seop) Really put soybean paste on it?
(Hee-seop) Benarkah ditaruh pasta kedelai di atasnya?
You agreed to do that.
Anda setuju untuk melakukan itu.
Quickly show me your face
Cepat tunjukkan wajahmu
(Hee-seop) Oh, by the way Do you think it's going to get a bit funny?
(Hee-seop) Oh, ngomong-ngomong Apakah menurut Anda ini akan menjadi sedikit lucu?
It smells like shit
Baunya seperti kotoran
(Soonae) Huh?
(Segera) Hah?
Quick!
Cepat!
(Heeseop) Ah... [lively music]
(Heeseop) Ah... [musik yang hidup]
You can't open your eyes [Heeseop’s embarrassed voice]
Anda tidak bisa membuka mata Anda [Suara malu Heeseop]
Yes, yes, yes, I understand.
Ya, ya, ya, saya mengerti.
[Heeseop’s nervous breathing]
[Nafas Heeseop gugup]
[Hee-seop's sound of pain]
[Suara kesakitan Hee-seop]
[Sniffles]
[Mengendus]
[Soon-ae smiles]
[Soon-ae tersenyum]
(Pure love) Who in this era Do you put soybean paste on it? You idiot
(Cinta murni) Siapa di era ini Apakah Anda menaruh pasta kedelai di atasnya? Dasar bodoh
(Hee-seop) [Laughing awkwardly] Ah, that...
(Hee-seop) [Tertawa canggung] Ah, itu...
[Heeseop clears his cough]
[Heeseop menghilangkan batuknya]
words
kata-kata
It's short?
Itu pendek?
no?
TIDAK?
ok
oke
(Heeseop) [Hesitating] But
(Heeseop) [Ragu-ragu] Tapi
Because I like it
Karena saya menyukainya
It's scary
Itu menakutkan
I guess you said to me
Saya kira Anda berkata kepada saya
I think it will become too precious
Saya pikir itu akan menjadi terlalu berharga
Why is that?
Mengapa demikian?
[Calm music]
[Musik yang tenang]
I could easily lose it
Saya bisa dengan mudah kehilangannya
Our tusks, our father, and our great son
Gading kami, ayah kami, dan putra buyut kami
I love you and love you
Aku mencintaimu dan mencintaimu
Everyone leave
Semuanya pergi
[Heeseop laughs]
[Heeseop tertawa]
[Sigh of pure love]
[Desahan cinta yang murni]
(Soonae) Um...
(Segera) Um...
I sometimes
saya kadang-kadang
When I feel lonely and scared
Saat aku merasa kesepian dan takut
Imagine a small door
Bayangkan sebuah pintu kecil
Small door?
Pintu kecil?
(Soonae) Yes
(Segera) Ya
There's a little door in my heart
Ada sebuah pintu kecil di hatiku
Behind that door
Di balik pintu itu
always me There is someone waiting for me
selalu aku Ada seseorang yang menungguku
You're scared too When I feel lonely
Kamu juga takut Saat aku merasa kesepian
Close your eyes and imagine that door
Tutup mata Anda dan bayangkan pintu itu
Then always I'll wait behind that door
Lalu selalu Aku akan menunggu di balik pintu itu
All you have to do is open it
Yang harus Anda lakukan adalah membukanya
Really?
Benarkah?
(Soonae) Yes
(Segera) Ya
[Heeseop’s surprised voice]
[Suara terkejut Heeseop]
(Heeseop) Huh?
(Heeseop) Hah?
[Dog barking in the distance]
[Anjing menggonggong di kejauhan]
[Heeseop chuckles]
[Heeseop terkekeh]
[heavy music]
[musik berat]
(Yoonyoung) Come to your senses, Lee Soon-ae
(Yoonyoung) Sadarlah, Lee Soon-ae
as much as you think Baek Hee-seop is also thinking of you.
sebanyak yang kamu pikirkan Baek Hee-seop juga memikirkanmu.
It's all your imagination
Itu semua hanya imajinasimu
What do you know that makes you say that?
Apa yang Anda ketahui sehingga membuat Anda berkata seperti itu?
[Sound of running footsteps]
[Suara langkah kaki berlari]
(Hyungman) Sunae!
(Hyungman) Sunae!
I'm disappointed in you
aku kecewa padamu
I'm disappointed, to my heart's content.
Saya kecewa, sepuasnya.
Let's end it now Because it will be much better for you
Mari kita akhiri sekarang Karena itu akan jauh lebih baik bagi Anda
[snapping sound]
[suara gertakan]
[shaking breathing]
[napas gemetar]
[Birdsong]
[Kicau Burung]
(Yuri) Really with my own two eyes I saw it clearly
(Yuri) Sungguh dengan kedua mataku sendiri Saya melihatnya dengan jelas
My mom and dad watched it together too. [Sounds of surprise from female students]
Ibu dan ayahku juga menontonnya bersama. [Suara kejutan dari siswi]
When we went on a picnic back then
Saat kami pergi piknik saat itu
He played the guitar amazingly There's that cute boy
Dia memainkan gitar dengan luar biasa Itu anak laki-laki lucu itu
(Female students) Yes
(Siswa perempuan) Ya
He's wearing handcuffs like this [Sounds of surprise from female students]
Dia memakai borgol seperti ini [Suara kejutan dari siswi]
(Yuri) With delicate eyes I was shaking so much
(Yuri) Dengan mata yang lembut Saya sangat gemetar
(Eunha) ‘He should have said’?
(Eunha) 'Seharusnya dia bilang'?
(Yuri) Her, her, her, her, her [secret music]
(Yuri) Dia, dia, dia, dia, dia [musik rahasia]
(Eunha) Oh, my, what’s really going on?
(Eunha) Ya ampun, apa yang sebenarnya terjadi?
(Female student) Do something like that Doesn't it look like that?
(Siswa perempuan) Lakukan sesuatu seperti itu Bukankah terlihat seperti itu?
(Yuri) So
(Yuri) Jadi
[Female students chattering]
[Siswa perempuan mengobrol]
stupid bastard
bajingan bodoh
You make things complicated
Anda membuat segalanya menjadi rumit
[The male students are noisy]
[Siswa laki-laki berisik]
(Byung-gu) Well, your homeroom teacher for personal reasons
(Byung-gu) Baiklah, wali kelasmu karena alasan pribadi
I haven't been able to come out for a few days.
Saya belum bisa keluar selama beberapa hari.
You all have been Don't cause trouble
Anda semua pernah mengalaminya Jangan menimbulkan masalah
Everyone should focus on their studies...
Setiap orang harus fokus pada studinya...
Who is that yet?
Siapa itu?
(Male student 1) It’s the murderer’s seat.
(Siswa laki-laki 1) Itu kursi si pembunuh.
[Boys giggle]
[Anak laki-laki terkikik]
[whispers]
[berbisik]
[Tapping sound] (Byunggu) Hey, you immature bastards.
[Mengetuk suara] (Byunggu) Hei, kamu bajingan yang belum dewasa.
I'm still not sure about anything To my classmate
Saya masih tidak yakin tentang apa pun Untuk teman sekelasku
Those are sounds like a big problem!
Kedengarannya seperti masalah besar!
(Male student 2) My father said that
(Siswa laki-laki 2) Ayah saya mengatakan itu
our village They say there is no one who would do such a rough thing.
desa kami Mereka bilang tidak ada orang yang mau melakukan hal kasar seperti itu.
But Baek Hee-seop is a transfer student.
Tapi Baek Hee-seop adalah murid pindahan.
Came from far away
Datang dari jauh
(Male student 3) Their uncle You're a police officer.
(Siswa laki-laki 3) Paman mereka Anda seorang petugas polisi.
But seeing as he was caught Isn’t it obvious?
Tapi mengingat dia tertangkap Bukankah sudah jelas?
[Boys are murmuring]
[Anak laki-laki bergumam]
[Calm music]
[Musik yang tenang]
[siren sound]
[suara sirene]
(Yoonyoung) Mom [Middle-aged Soon-ae’s moans]
(Yoonyoung) Ibu [Erangan Soon-ae paruh baya]
[Crying] Mom, ah, mom, mom
[Menangis] Ibu, ah, ibu, ibu
- (Nurse) Are you okay? - Mom, Mom
- (Perawat) Apakah kamu baik-baik saja? - Bu, Bu
(Yoonyoung) Mom, ah, mom
(Yoonyoung) Bu, ah, bu
(Nurse) Guardian
(Perawat) Wali
Are there any adults here?
Apakah ada orang dewasa di sini?
Wait a minute [Nervous breathing]
Tunggu sebentar [Nafas gugup]
[Call connection tone]
[Nada sambungan panggilan]
Where have you been all day, today?
Kemana saja kamu sepanjang hari ini?
Your uncle has some trouble...
Pamanmu punya masalah...
(Middle-aged Hee-seop) Why? [Yoonyoung’s trembling breathing]
(Hee-seop paruh baya) Mengapa? [Nafas Yoonyoung yang gemetar]
[Middle-aged Hee-seop's puzzled voice]
[Suara bingung Hee-seop paruh baya]
(Yoonyoung) My father
(Yoonyoung) Ayahku
He chose his brother again this time.
Dia memilih saudaranya lagi kali ini.
no matter how sad mom is
betapapun sedihnya ibu
No matter how twisted your life gets Just like that again
Tidak peduli betapa kacaunya hidupmu Sama seperti itu lagi
To my uncle, we
Untuk pamanku, kami
I was just pushed out.
Saya baru saja didorong keluar.
Like it's been like this all my life
Sepertinya sudah seperti ini sepanjang hidupku
[Haejun sighs]
[Haejun menghela nafas]
Seoul is quite large.
Seoul cukup besar.
Even if his younger brother is captured instead
Bahkan jika adik laki-lakinya malah ditangkap
I'm a person who pretends not to know and hides.
Aku adalah orang yang pura-pura tidak tahu dan bersembunyi.
It's even weirder that it's easy to find
Yang lebih aneh lagi adalah mudah ditemukan
we were wrong
kami salah
What Baek Hee-seop tried to cover up
Apa yang Baek Hee-seop coba tutupi
It wasn't murder
Itu bukan pembunuhan
[Meaningful music]
[Musik yang bermakna]
(Haejun) It was strange.
(Haejun) Itu aneh.
Even before we came Even without a confession or anything like that.
Bahkan sebelum kami datang Bahkan tanpa pengakuan atau semacamnya.
Baek Hee-seop was equally a suspect.
Baek Hee-seop juga menjadi tersangka.
the shirt, the lock
bajunya, kuncinya
They say it's all theirs I said it wasn't just murder.
Mereka bilang itu semua milik mereka Saya bilang itu bukan hanya pembunuhan.
A person determined to overwrite Sin is denial?
Seseorang bertekad untuk menimpa Dosa adalah penyangkalan?
That's it
Itu saja
Because I think the evidence will become ambiguous. Trying to get out...
Karena menurut saya buktinya akan menjadi ambigu. Mencoba keluar...
no
tidak
It wasn't really
Sebenarnya tidak
(Haejun) To everyone I met there I asked the same question
(Haejun) Kepada semua orang yang saya temui di sana Saya menanyakan pertanyaan yang sama
The last time I saw Baek Yu-seop was When was it?
Terakhir kali aku melihat Baek Yu-seop adalah Kapan itu?
[Sound of men talking]
[Suara pria berbicara]
(Man 1) I don’t know, I would never
(Man 1) Saya tidak tahu, saya tidak akan pernah tahu
Oh, we live in the same boarding house How do you know everything?
Oh, kami tinggal di kost yang sama Bagaimana kamu tahu segalanya?
we don't know anything don't ask
kita tidak tahu apa-apa jangan tanya
[Man 2 clears his throat]
[Pria 2 berdehem]
(Man 3) That night
(Pria 3) Malam itu
Being dragged to the front like that Even though I saw it clearly with my own two eyes
Diseret ke depan seperti itu Padahal aku melihatnya dengan jelas dengan kedua mataku sendiri
I couldn't do anything
Saya tidak bisa berbuat apa-apa
I couldn't even think of chasing after you.
Aku bahkan tidak terpikir untuk mengejarmu.
(Woman 1) I lost a lot of blood.
(Wanita 1) Saya kehilangan banyak darah.
[Crying] After getting hurt like that Did you run away well?
[Menangis] Setelah terluka seperti itu Apakah kamu melarikan diri dengan baik?
Since that day There are no kids I can contact.
Sejak hari itu Tidak ada anak yang bisa saya hubungi.
I'm so worried
Saya sangat khawatir
[Woman 1 sobs] (Haejun) I pretended not to know half of the time.
[Wanita 1 terisak] (Haejun) Aku pura-pura tidak tahu separuh waktu.
I told half the story.
Saya menceritakan separuh cerita.
That night of the 16th Everyone was watching Baek Yu-seop.
Malam itu tanggal 16 Semua orang memperhatikan Baek Yu-seop.
And that too in the middle of Seoul
Dan itu juga di tengah kota Seoul
(Yoonyoung) Wait a minute Then my father...
(Yoonyoung) Tunggu sebentar Lalu ayahku...
Unless it's Baek Yu-seop
Kecuali itu Baek Yu-seop
my father What happens now?
ayahku Apa yang terjadi sekarang?
But that shirt It will help you
Tapi baju itu Ini akan membantu Anda
What the police want Because it won't be there
Apa yang diinginkan polisi Karena itu tidak akan ada di sana
Still
Tetap saja
[nervous music]
[musik gugup]
Still, maybe...
Tetap saja, mungkin...
(Class president) Let’s see. [Class leader clears his throat]
(Ketua kelas) Mari kita lihat. [Ketua kelas berdehem]
‘Blood stains on shirt’
‘Noda darah di baju’
‘Blood type is A’
'Golongan darah adalah A'
Huh? Type A?
Hah? Tipe A?
Hey, the blood types of the victims. How did you say it would happen?
Hei, golongan darah korbannya. Bagaimana menurut Anda hal itu akan terjadi?
(Detective 3) Jooyoung Lee is type O Lee Kyung-ae is type B.
(Detektif 3) Jooyoung Lee adalah tipe O Lee Kyung-ae adalah tipe B.
(Class President) Then what about this kid?
(Ketua Kelas) Lalu bagaimana dengan anak ini?
- I'm type O. - (Class leader) What?
- Aku tipe O. - (Ketua kelas) Apa?
What is this?
Apa ini?
Whose blood is this?
Darah siapa ini?
IC
IC
[Sound of approaching footsteps]
[Suara langkah kaki mendekat]
- (Detective 4) Hello, how are you? - (Detective 5) Hello.
- (Detektif 4) Halo, apa kabar? - (Detektif 5) Halo.
(Detective 4) [Sarcastic tone] Thank you for your hard work
(Detektif 4) [Nada sarkastik] Terima kasih atas kerja keras Anda
(Detective 3) Who...
(Detektif 3) Siapa...
I am a Korean family from Seoul.
Saya keluarga Korea dari Seoul.
(Detective 4) To our chief I called in advance
(Detektif 4) Kepada ketua kami Saya menelepon terlebih dahulu
How come it wasn't delivered?
Kok tidak terkirim?
- (Detective 2) Huh? - (Class President) Well, ah, yes, yes
- (Detektif 2) Hah? - (Ketua Kelas) Ya, ya, ya
(Detective 5) Why is this happening? Have you been doing unnecessary things?
(Detektif 5) Mengapa ini terjadi? Pernahkah Anda melakukan hal-hal yang tidak perlu?
It probably won't be his anyway.
Lagipula itu mungkin bukan miliknya.
Right, Hee-seop?
Benar, Hee-seop?
(Dongsik) What is it!
(Dongsik) Ada apa!
(Detective 4) What is it?
(Detektif 4) Ada apa?
I did something worse than murder They're going to catch college students.
Saya melakukan sesuatu yang lebih buruk dari pembunuhan Mereka akan menangkap mahasiswa.
[nervous music]
[musik gugup]
Hey, Hee-seop?
Hei, Hee-seop?
you have to come with us now
kamu harus ikut dengan kami sekarang
[Small] To find your brother Baek Yu-seop
[Kecil] Untuk menemukan saudaramu Baek Yu-seop
(Detective 5) Baby I knew, we were coming?
(Detektif 5) Sayang Aku tahu, kami akan datang?
(Dongsik) Hey! Hey, you guy! [Urgent music]
(Dongsik) Hei! Hei, kalian! [Musik yang mendesak]
[Detectives trying to stop him] Okay, okay.
[Detektif mencoba menghentikannya] Oke oke.
Okay, let it go for a moment! Mr.
Oke, biarkan sebentar! Tuan.
Okay, just talking about it...
Oke, langsung saja ngobrol...
[Car door sound] Hey, you bastards!
[Suara pintu mobil] Hei, kamu bajingan!
Hey Hee-seop! Heeseop!
Hei Hee-seop! Heeseop!
Don’t worry, hey Hee-seop!
Jangan khawatir, hei Hee-seop!
My uncle will save me
Pamanku akan menyelamatkanku
Hey, you bastards!
Hei, kamu bajingan!
Hey, you bastards, Heeseop! Heeseop! [Car starting sound]
Hei, kamu bajingan, Heeseop! Heeseop! [Suara start mobil]
Hey Hee-seop! Heeseop!
Hei Hee-seop! Heeseop!
Hey, you bastards!
Hei, kamu bajingan!
wait here
tunggu di sini
[nervous music]
[musik gugup]
[Detective 5’s encouraging voice]
[Suara penyemangat Detektif 5]
[Soaring music] [Frightened breathing]
[Musik yang melonjak] [Nafas ketakutan]
[Embarrassed breathing]
[Napas yang memalukan]
[Oncoming car engine sound]
[Suara mesin mobil datang]
[shaking breathing] [dark music]
[napas gemetar] [musik gelap]
(Yoonyoung) [Muttering] Dad, Dad
(Yoonyoung) [Bergumam] Ayah, Ayah
Baek Yu-seop, Baek Yu-seop
Baek Yu-seop, Baek Yu-seop
[Crying] Baek Yu-seop
[Menangis] Baek Yu-seop
Baek Yu-seop
Baek Yu-seop
(Yoonyoung) I brought my father’s luggage.
(Yoonyoung) Saya membawa barang bawaan ayah saya.
Just buy it here. Take it easy
Beli saja di sini. Tenang saja
While my mother was hospitalized Have you been there even once?
Sementara ibu saya dirawat di rumah sakit Apakah kamu pernah ke sana sekali saja?
- But here! - (Middle-aged Hee-seop) There
- Tapi di sini! - (Hee-seop paruh baya) Di sana
You are there
Anda berada di sana
So, that's it.
Jadi, itu saja.
We don't need a father, neither do we
Kami tidak membutuhkan seorang ayah, kami juga tidak
(Yunyoung) I’m sick of it.
(Yunyoung) Aku muak dengan itu.
Just in case
Untuk berjaga-jaga
Even if it's late Maybe my father will come
Meski terlambat Mungkin ayahku akan datang
Even though I knew you wouldn’t come I keep waiting
Meskipun aku tahu kamu tidak akan datang Saya terus menunggu
I hate that even more!
Aku semakin membencinya!
(Middle-aged Yusuf) It’s scary.
(Yusuf paruh baya) Menakutkan.
I'm scared, Hee-seop
Aku takut, Hee-seop
Hee-seop
Hee-seop
Let's hide [Nervous breathing]
Ayo bersembunyi [Nafas gugup]
Hee-seop, you have to hide.
Hee-seop, kamu harus bersembunyi.
Hee-seop, let’s hide.
Hee-seop, ayo bersembunyi.
hiding
bersembunyi
[Meaningful sound effects]
[Efek suara yang bermakna]
[shaking breathing] [Soaring music]
[napas gemetar] [Musik yang melonjak]
[intense music]
[musik yang intens]
Continue the same path?
Lanjutkan jalan yang sama?
[Meaningful music]
[Musik yang bermakna]
[Rough breathing]
[Nafas kasar]
Hee-seop
Hee-seop
Where is our Hee-seop now?
Dimana Hee-seop kita sekarang?
(Detective 6) You bastard, blow! Blow, you bastard
(Detektif 6) Dasar bajingan, tiup! Pukulan, bajingan
[Heeseop’s painful moans] You bastard
[erangan menyakitkan Heeseop] Kamu bajingan
(Detective 4) Hey, come out Hey, come out, come out!
(Detektif 4) Hei, keluar Hei, keluar, keluar!
[panting sound]
[suara terengah-engah]
[stomping sound] [Painful groan]
[suara menghentak] [Erangan yang menyakitkan]
[Heeseop cries]
[Heeseop menangis]
[Rough breathing]
[Nafas kasar]
Where is our Yusuf now?
Dimana Yusuf kita sekarang?
[Screaming scared]
[Berteriak ketakutan]
Hee-seop
Hee-seop
It hurts
Itu menyakitkan
Let's take it easy
Mari kita santai saja
I don't know
Saya tidak tahu
You don't know!
Anda tidak tahu!
[Heeseop’s heavy breathing]
[Nafas berat Heeseop]
[sigh]
[menghela nafas]
Then I have to save your memory.
Kalau begitu aku harus menyimpan ingatanmu.
[Screaming scared]
[Berteriak ketakutan]
[Painful groan]
[Erangan yang menyakitkan]
(Yusuf) Murder?
(Yusuf) Pembunuhan?
who? Who died?
WHO? Siapa yang meninggal?
[Yuseop’s trembling breathing]
[Nafas Yuseop yang gemetar]
How did something happen like that...
Bagaimana hal seperti itu bisa terjadi...
that shirt is mine [nervous music]
baju itu milikku [musik gugup]
Hee-seop, Hee-seop I already knew everything
Hee-seop, Hee-seop Saya sudah tahu segalanya
where was i that night What have you done!
dimana aku malam itu Apa yang telah kamu lakukan!
[groans with difficulty]
[mengerang dengan susah payah]
[Coughing]
[Batuk]
(Detective 4) [Sighing] Hee-seop
(Detektif 4) [Menghela nafas] Hee-seop
[Heeseop’s scared breathing]
[Nafas Heeseop yang ketakutan]
[groan]
[mengerang]
[Heeseop’s scream]
[Teriakan Heeseop]
that night
malam itu
[stomping sound] [screaming]
[suara menghentak] [berteriak]
run away from us
lari dari kami
Your brother came to see you
Kakakmu datang menemuimu
Right?
Benar?
[Heeseop’s scream]
[Teriakan Heeseop]
[Rough breathing]
[Nafas kasar]
[Hee-seop sobs]
[Hee-seop terisak]
(Heeseop) I’ve never been like that.
(Heeseop) Saya belum pernah seperti itu.
(Detective 5) Ah, Hee-seop.
(Detektif 5) Ah, Hee-seop.
Yes, Hee-seop, yes.
Ya, Hee-seop, ya.
[Heeseop’s scared voice] Heeseop, uh, yeah
[Suara ketakutan Heeseop] Heeseop, eh, ya
Do you know where this is?
Tahukah kamu dimana ini?
You wouldn't even dare to guess It's that kind of place
Anda bahkan tidak berani menebaknya Itu tempat seperti itu
Police stations in every corner It's on a different level.
Kantor polisi di setiap sudut Itu berada pada level yang berbeda.
if you go wrong here
jika kamu salah disini
Without even the mouse or the bird knowing It's going away, huh?
Tanpa sepengetahuan tikus atau burung Itu akan hilang, ya?
[Sobbing]
[Menangis]
[Heeseop mumbles]
[Heeseop bergumam]
- (Heeseop) I... - (Detective 5) Huh?
- (Heeseop) Aku... - (Detektif 5) Hah?
(Detective 4) Oh
(Detektif 4) Oh
Be ignorant
Jadilah bodoh
I don't know much about that.
Saya tidak tahu banyak tentang itu.
[Detective 5 laughs] [Hee-seop sobs]
[Detektif 5 tertawa] [Hee-seop terisak]
(Detective 5) Oh, it’s annoying, it’s annoying [Detective 4 sighs]
(Detektif 5) Oh, menjengkelkan, menjengkelkan [Detektif 4 menghela nafas]
It's annoying [Cries]
Itu menjengkelkan [Menangis]
[희섭의 거친 숨소리]
[Nafas berat Heeseop]
(Detective 5) What do you think? 어때, 이제 기억이 나?
(Detektif 5) Bagaimana menurut anda? Bagaimana kamu mengingatnya sekarang?
말할 수 있겠어, 없겠어?
Bisakah kamu mengatakannya atau tidak?
아, 안 되겠구나, 간다!
Oh, itu tidak akan berhasil, ayo pergi!
castle?
kastil?
(희섭) 성, 뭔 일이여?
(Hee-seop) Seong, apa yang terjadi?
[유섭의 힘겨운 숨소리] [heavy music]
[Nafas Yuseop sesak] [musik berat]
Hee-seop
Hee-seop
Last name, no...
Nama belakang, tidak...
[유섭의 거친 숨소리]
[Napas berat Yuseop]
[희섭의 당황한 숨소리]
[Napas Heeseop yang malu]
(Yuseop) Heeseop
(Yuseop) Heeseop
(Heeseop) Uh, uh
(Heeseop) Uh, uh
[Yuseop’s moans] 아, 이게, 이게 뭐여? uh?
[erangan Yuseop] Apa ini? eh?
What is this?
Apa ini?
결국 또 데모한 거여?
Apakah Anda akhirnya melakukan demo lagi?
Are you doing that again?
Apakah kamu melakukan itu lagi?
I'm sorry, Hee-seop.
Maafkan aku, Hee Seop.
My brother
Saudaraku
I'm sorry bro
Maafkan aku kawan
[Angry breathing]
[Nafas marah]
내가 다신 그딴 위험한 짓 I told you not to do it, right? uh?
Saya tidak akan pernah melakukan hal berbahaya seperti itu lagi Sudah kubilang jangan lakukan itu, kan? eh?
두 번 다시 하지 말랬지!
Sudah kubilang jangan lakukan itu lagi!
[유섭의 힘겨운 숨소리]
[Nafas Yuseop sesak]
[Heeseop’s surprised voice]
[Suara terkejut Heeseop]
(Heeseop) Huh?
(Heeseop) Hah?
[Yuseop’s embarrassed voice]
[Suara Yuseop yang malu]
[Yuseop’s heavy breathing]
[Napas berat Yuseop]
Where did you go?
Kemana kamu pergi?
You bastard
Kamu bajingan
You ugly bastard!
Dasar bajingan jelek!
[Heeseop’s heavy breathing]
[Nafas berat Heeseop]
(Heeseop) Have you forgotten everything?
(Heeseop) Apakah kamu lupa semuanya?
uh?
eh?
Have you forgotten all this?
Apakah kamu sudah melupakan semua ini?
If I forgot
Jika saya lupa
Are you going to do this, Heeseop?
Apakah kamu akan melakukan ini, Heeseop?
(Young Yusuf) Father, mother! [The sound of young Yusuf’s heavy breathing]
(Yusuf Muda) Ayah, ibu! [Suara nafas berat Yusuf muda]
You're in big trouble
Anda berada dalam masalah besar
Guns are fired on the street and people die.
Senjata ditembakkan di jalan dan orang-orang mati.
(Heeseop Mo) Hey?
(Heeseop Mo) Hei?
Yusuf, what did he eat wrong? Jinseop's father
Yusuf, apa yang salah dia makan? Ayah Jinseop
It's not even summer yet I must have eaten the heat.
Ini bahkan belum musim panas Aku pasti sudah makan panasnya.
(Young Yusup) Oh, that’s right!
(Yusup Muda) Oh, benar!
(Hee-seop’s mother) Oh, come on in. Don't talk nonsense
(Ibu Hee-seop) Oh, ayo masuk. Jangan bicara omong kosong
- (Woman 2) Jinseop’s mom! Oh my - (Hee-seop) Why?
- (Wanita 2) Ibu Jinseop! Ya ampun - (Hee-seop) Kenapa?
(Woman 2) Oh my, Jinseop’s mom.
(Wanita 2) Ya ampun, ibu Jinseop.
Let's go to the hospital I think you should go and use it.
Ayo pergi ke rumah sakit Saya pikir Anda harus pergi dan menggunakannya.
Oh, why?
Kenapa?
Azim, what do you mean by that?
Azim, apa maksudmu dengan itu?
Oh my, ah, that school over there Students demonstrating
Ya ampun, ah, sekolah di sana itu Siswa berdemonstrasi
I've been shot so many times
Saya telah ditembak berkali-kali
(Woman 2) I put it in a sack and hung it. They pushed it all over the place.
(Wanita 2) Saya memasukkannya ke dalam karung dan menggantungnya. Mereka mendorongnya ke mana-mana.
Doesn’t Jinseop go to that school?
Bukankah Jinseop bersekolah di sekolah itu?
[heavy music] [Gunshots ringing in the distance]
[musik berat] [Suara tembakan terdengar dari kejauhan]
(Brothers) [Sobbing] Tusk
(Saudara-saudara) [Menangis] Tusk
With my tusk and my father I'll be back soon
Dengan gadingku dan ayahku Saya akan segera kembali
I will definitely come to Neg Castle.
Saya pasti akan datang ke Kastil Neg.
You must never come out?
Anda tidak boleh keluar?
Tusk
Gading
(Hee-seop) What if something happens?
(Hee-seop) Bagaimana jika terjadi sesuatu?
[snapping sound] Yu-seop, Hee-seop
[suara gertakan] Yu-seop, Hee-seop
I know they are sad for each other
Aku tahu mereka sedih satu sama lain
Even if it's just the two of us, we'll definitely ditch
Meskipun hanya kami berdua, kami pasti akan meninggalkannya
must live well
harus hidup dengan baik
(Young Hee-seop) Tusk
(Hee-seop Muda) Gading
Do you have a promise with this tusk?
Apakah Anda punya janji dengan gading ini?
(Brothers) [Crying] Tusks, tusks!
(Saudara-saudara) [Menangis] Gading, gading!
- (Young Hee-seop) Tusk, father! - (Young Yusuf) Tusks!
- (Hee-seop Muda) Gading, ayah! - (Yusuf Muda) Gading!
[Brother cries]
[Saudara menangis]
[Multiple gunshots]
[Beberapa tembakan]
[gunshot] [Static sound effect]
[tembakan] [Efek suara statis]
[ringing footsteps]
[dering langkah kaki]
How could I forget that day?
Bagaimana saya bisa melupakan hari itu?
Hee-seop
Hee-seop
(Yuseop) That gunshot sound at that time How could I forget
(Yuseop) Suara tembakan saat itu Bagaimana saya bisa lupa
(Heeseop) Well then
(Heeseop) Kalau begitu
So what about the tusk promise?
Lalu bagaimana dengan janji gadingnya?
Even if I lose you How should I live!
Bahkan jika aku kehilanganmu Bagaimana aku harus hidup!
(Yuseop) Then what should I do!
(Yuseop) Lalu apa yang harus aku lakukan!
huh?
Hah?
Tusk
Gading
[Crying] Father
[Menangis] Ayah
our last name
nama belakang kami
Losing everything
Kehilangan segalanya
It's unfair
Itu tidak adil
What should I do because I’m upset?
Apa yang harus saya lakukan karena saya kesal?
[Sound of pounding chest]
[Suara dada berdebar kencang]
There was a fire inside
Ada api di dalam
How can you live quietly, Hee-seop?
Bagaimana kamu bisa hidup dengan tenang, Hee-seop?
how
bagaimana
[Yuseop sobs]
[Yuseop terisak]
[Heeseop sighs]
[Heeseop menghela nafas]
How, how do you live?
Bagaimana, bagaimana kamu hidup?
[Sad music]
[Musik sedih]
[Sobbing] Just now I found someone I like
[Menangis] Baru saja Saya menemukan seseorang yang saya sukai
I haven't done anything good yet There's nothing
Saya belum melakukan sesuatu yang baik Tidak ada apa-apa
[Coughing]
[Batuk]
[sigh]
[menghela nafas]
[Heeseop’s trembling breathing]
[Nafas Heeseop yang gemetar]
Quickly take off your clothes, okay?
Cepat buka bajumu, oke?
I'll make sure you never get caught
Saya akan memastikan Anda tidak pernah tertangkap
Hee-seop
Hee-seop
(Heeseop) Ah, hurry up! Mr.
(Heeseop) Ah, cepatlah! Tuan.
I wish I could lose you too
Aku berharap aku bisa kehilanganmu juga
Are you going to buy it?
Apakah Anda akan membelinya?
[Sobbing]
[Menangis]
[Both crying]
[Keduanya menangis]
(Yuseop) Heeseop
(Yuseop) Heeseop
[Heeseop’s labored breathing] [Lonely music]
[Nafas Heeseop sesak] [Musik yang sepi]
(Heeseop’s mother) [Sobbing] my poor baby
(Ibu Heeseop) [Menangis] bayiku yang malang
Oh my, what the hell?
Ya ampun, apa-apaan ini?
Yu-seop, Hee-seop
Yu-seop, Hee-seop
I know they are sad for each other
Aku tahu mereka sedih satu sama lain
Even if it's just the two of us, we'll definitely ditch [shaking breathing]
Meskipun hanya kami berdua, kami pasti akan meninggalkannya [napas gemetar]
must live well
harus hidup dengan baik
You have to live to the fullest, right?
Anda harus hidup sepenuhnya, bukan?
[Sobbing]
[Menangis]
Tusk
Gading
I'm scared
saya takut
[Sound of dripping water]
[Suara air menetes]
[Yuseop’s trembling breathing]
[Nafas Yuseop yang gemetar]
[heavy music]
[musik berat]
I'm the one they're looking for
Akulah yang mereka cari
please
tolong
(Yuseop) Please
(Yuseop) Tolong
please tell me my sister Please take me with you
tolong beritahu aku adikku Tolong bawa aku bersamamu
[heavy music]
[musik berat]
(Yuseop) Come in.
(Yuseop) Masuklah.
(Haejun) Mr. Yoonyoung
(Haejun) Tuan Yoonyoung
Are you here?
Apakah kamu di sini?
In here?
Di sini?
(Haejun) Yes, I saw it with my own eyes.
(Haejun) Ya, saya melihatnya dengan mata kepala sendiri.
I'll bring you
aku akan membawamu
(Haejun) No
(Haejun) Tidak
that's not a good way
itu bukan cara yang baik
I have an idea Don't worry, wait here
Saya punya ide Jangan khawatir, tunggu di sini
What is a good way? There isn't any here anyway.
Apa cara yang baik? Lagi pula tidak ada apa-apa di sini.
(Yuseop) Instead of me If something goes wrong with our Hee-seop
(Yuseop) Daripada aku Jika ada yang tidak beres dengan Hee-seop kami
I no longer
saya tidak lagi
I can't live anymore
Saya tidak bisa hidup lagi
through my way When our Hee-seop is released
melalui jalanku Saat Hee-seop kami dibebaskan
Please take care of me then
Tolong jaga aku kalau begitu
[Moon So-ri]
[Bulan So-ri]
It's dangerous, so wait here.
Ini berbahaya, jadi tunggu di sini.
[Sound of door closing]
[Suara pintu ditutup]
[Sound of door opening]
[Suara pintu terbuka]
[Sound of being dragged]
[Suara diseret]
[Lonely music] [Sound of footsteps dragging]
[Musik yang sepi] [Suara langkah kaki menyeret]
[Yoonyoung’s urgent breathing]
[Napas mendesak Yoonyoung]
Are you okay?
Apakah kamu baik-baik saja?
[Sound of relief]
[Suara lega]
It's okay
Tidak apa-apa
(Heeseop) I made a mistake
(Heeseop) Saya membuat kesalahan
Being punished
Dihukum
It's natural
Itu wajar
What did you do wrong?
Apa kesalahanmu?
(Heeseop) I made a mistake
(Heeseop) Saya membuat kesalahan
To Grannie
Untuk Nenek
This is how it all turned out
Inilah yang terjadi
[Crying] I don’t mean it.
[Menangis] Aku tidak bermaksud begitu.
Why does this happen?
Mengapa ini terjadi?
If not, then why?
Jika tidak, lalu mengapa?
[shaking breathing]
[napas gemetar]
Is this going to happen to us?
Apakah ini akan terjadi pada kita?
Bye
Sampai jumpa
Do you know what I did wrong?
Tahukah kamu apa kesalahanku?
Ah, what did we do wrong?
Ah, kesalahan apa yang kita lakukan?
Do you know?
Tahukah kamu?
(Yoonyoung) Who am I?
(Yoonyoung) Siapa aku?
Where are we now? [Heeseop’s crying]
Dimana kita sekarang? [Heeseop menangis]
[shaking breathing]
[napas gemetar]
I have passed such a long time Is it true for you?
Aku telah melewati waktu yang begitu lama Apakah itu benar bagi Anda?
What answer should I give?
Jawaban apa yang harus saya berikan?
Without knowing anything I'm just like a fool
Tanpa mengetahui apapun Aku seperti orang bodoh
here
di sini
in your darkest night
di malam tergelapmu
I [Sobbing]
saya [Menangis]
[Heeseop’s crying]
[Heeseop menangis]
[Emotional music]
[Musik emosional]
(Haejun) Have you collected all these things?
(Haejun) Sudahkah kamu mengumpulkan semua ini?
(Middle-aged Yeonwoo) When we were dating in the past Movie tickets I saw
(Yeonwoo paruh baya) Saat kami berkencan di masa lalu Tiket film yang saya lihat
With your mother?
Dengan ibumu?
(Middle-aged Yeonwoo) The first time we saw each other What was the movie about?
(Yeonwoo paruh baya) Pertama kali kami bertemu Tentang apa film itu?
‘Our happy young days’
‘Hari-hari muda kita yang bahagia’
But I couldn't see it because I was sleeping
Tapi aku tidak bisa melihatnya karena aku sedang tidur
(Misook) Teacher
(Misook) Guru
hello
halo
Subtitle: Jang Se-ri
Subtitle: Jang Se-ri